[
  [
    "— You could have knelt down , damn it , Kinch , when your dying mother asked you , Buck Mulligan said .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Buck Mulligan": "PER"
        },
        {
          "your dying mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "No boy of fourteen can smoke without being affected injuriously .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "No boy of fourteen": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I am sure she will be an excellent servant ; and it will be a great comfort to poor Miss Taylor to have somebody about her that she is used to see .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Miss Taylor": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an excellent servant": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "It takes a lot of water , and running strong , to sweep the outside edge of a river clear .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "It was his mother .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He had been fidgetting , and with natural intuition she felt a certain interest growing in that quarter .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He stamped and shook the snow from off himself in the bar , and followed Mrs. Hall into her guest parlour to strike his bargain .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the bar": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "Mrs. Hall": "PER"
        },
        {
          "her guest parlour": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I said .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "One winter day I presented Turkey with a highly-respectable looking coat of my own , a padded gray coat , of a most comfortable warmth , and which buttoned straight up from the knee to the neck .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "So did more than one of them .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He looked in vain into the stalls for the butcher who had sold fresh meat twice a week , on market days , and he felt a genuine thrill of pleasure when he recognized the red bandana turban of old Aunt Lyddy , the ancient negro woman who had sold him gingerbread and fried fish , and told him weird tales of witchcraft and conjuration , in the old days when , as an idle boy , he had loafed about the market-house .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "an idle boy": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the market-house": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "the butcher who had sold fresh meat twice a week , on market days": "PER"
        },
        {
          "old Aunt Lyddy": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "My days seemed to melt away in a dream of pink and purple peace .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "There is no reply .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "There was now riding off in all directions to the doctor ’s , to the farrier ’s , and no doubt to Squire Gordon ’s , to let him know about his son .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his son": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the farrier": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the doctor": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Squire Gordon": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Why , when I was a nipper every morning of my life I had a cold bath , winter and summer .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a nipper": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "So , while more or less fortunate little rich boys were defying governesses on the beach at Newport , or being spanked or tutored or read to from “ Do and Dare , ” or “ Frank on the Mississippi , ” Amory was biting acquiescent bell-boys in the Waldorf , outgrowing a natural repugnance to chamber music and symphonies , and deriving a highly specialized education from his mother .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his mother": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the Mississippi": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the beach": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "acquiescent bell-boys": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the Waldorf": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "May be cinnabar in it . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "II .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Where 'd you get your money ? \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Oh , Rudolf , how good of you !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "By my advice , she endeavoured to procure proofs of her marriage-but in vain ; her credulity had been no match for his art .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Had the man lost his mind ?",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the man": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The bright morning sun , therefore , shone on broad shoulders and well-developed busts , and on round and ruddy cheeks , that had ripened in the far-off island , and had hardly yet grown paler or thinner in the atmosphere of New England .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "New England": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the far-off island": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He held her up by the leg torn and bleeding , and all the gentlemen seemed well pleased .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "all the gentlemen": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He and his wife , the old lady who had received me , looked at each other in a frightened sort of way .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the old lady who had received me": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his wife": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "She noticed that the melting snow that still sprinkled his shoulders dripped upon her carpet .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "No written record of this dispute is known to be in existence .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She could not help smiling as he told her of some popular actress of whom she reminded him .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "some popular actress of whom she reminded him": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The Return THERE WAS SOMETHING about the coast town of Dunnet which made it seem more attractive than other maritime villages of eastern Maine .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "eastern Maine": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "other maritime villages of eastern Maine": "GPE"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Death is not more still than is this Virginian land in the hour when the sun has sunk away , and it is black beneath the trees , and the stars brighten slowly and softly , one by one .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Oh , Lucy ! ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "There is magic in it .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Oh , a view !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "he said , running to the dresser for his cap .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ You mistake me , my dear .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my dear": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Letter 1 St. Petersburgh , Dec. 11th , 17 -- TO Mrs. Saville , England You will rejoice to hear that no disaster has accompanied the commencement of an enterprise which you have regarded with such evil forebodings .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Mrs. Saville": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Ees .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Oh !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "What made you tease me so ?",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" For Becky Sharp , \" answered Jemima , trembling very much , and blushing over her withered face and neck , as she turned her back on her sister .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "her sister": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Becky Sharp": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "You ought to see some of them .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Holmes was sitting with his back to me , and I had given him no sign of my occupation .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "* * * * * The wide playgrounds were swarming with boys .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "But Sidney said : “ Well , now , if I did n't think you sewed his collar with white thread , but it 's black . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "And with her straight , unfathomable glance she answered that she would be so , of course .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He was above doing anything mean or dishonorable .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Have you relatives ? ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She only knew that people were ill and that she heard mysterious and frightening sounds .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "What if it be stagnant and slimy here ?",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He was a man whom prosperity harmed .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a man whom prosperity harmed": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "In truth the masquerade licence of the night was nearly unlimited ; but the figure in question had out-Heroded Herod , and gone beyond the bounds of even the prince 's indefinite decorum .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the prince": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the figure in question": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "At the rear door of the car there was no platform , but a step where passengers clung in wet clumps when the weather was bad and the car crowded .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the car": "VEH"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Her letter is violent , sometimes abusive , and that of you !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The trotting horse had halted out there somewhere .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "In taking an occasional wisdom-giving stroll in Mrs. Todd ’s company , and in acting as business partner during her frequent absences , I found the July days fly fast , and it was not until I felt myself confronted with too great pride and pleasure in the display , one night , of two dollars and twenty-seven cents which I had taken in during the day , that I remembered a long piece of writing , sadly belated now , which I was bound to do .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Mrs. Todd": "PER"
        },
        {
          "business partner": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Daily , on the library steps or in the hall of the Main Building , the co-eds talked of “ What shall we do when we finish college ? ”",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the Main Building": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "the co-eds": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "You 've had enough already . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "‘ Ah ! ’",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I should not allow any one to inconvenience me , if I could hinder it -- walk in ! '",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" It 's so dreadful to be poor ! \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "And it is , by the way , from the _ presence _ of others that we really derive support in our dark hours of grief , and not from their talk , which often only serves to irritate us .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "A bowl of white china had stood beside her deathbed holding the green sluggish bile which she had torn up from her rotting liver by fits of loud groaning vomiting .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Then , of course , the fun began .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Hand me that switch . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "HOWARDS END , TUESDAY .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "HOWARDS END": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He became an exquisite dandy , amassed a rather pathetic collection of silk pajamas , brocaded dressing-gowns , and neckties too flamboyant to wear ; in this secret finery he would parade before a mirror in his room or lie stretched in satin along his window-seat looking down on the yard and realizing dimly this clamor , breathless and immediate , in which it seemed he was never to have a part .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the yard": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "an exquisite dandy": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I wanted these . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "However , he never had any fits ( which was encouraging ) ; and before the natural outbursts of impatience on the part of his father he could always , in his childhood ’s days , run for protection behind the short skirts of his sister Winnie .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his father": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his sister": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "It was to me in particular that he appeared to propound this -- appeared almost to appeal for aid not to hesitate .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "she answered nervously .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ How much did the other mug get ? ”",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the other mug": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He always felt shy and awkward here , and wanted to hide behind things for fear some one might laugh at him .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "It was such a grief to his mother . \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "After being cast aside by this young man , the slave-woman betook herself to the business of a laundress , and was considered to be the most tasteful woman in Richmond at her vocation .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a laundress": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the slave": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the slave-woman": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Most of the women were of the kind vaguely called emancipated , and professed some protest against male supremacy .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the women": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Most of the women": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "She had heard that he was a very young officer who had just come from England .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a very young officer who had just come from England": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "yo !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "And the Brahmins heard , and bowed before his will .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the Brahmins": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The other officers were coarse , illiterate fellows , but little above the villainous crew they bullied , and were only too glad to avoid social intercourse with the polished English noble and his lady , so that the Claytons were left very much to themselves .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his lady": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the Claytons": "PER"
        },
        {
          "coarse , illiterate fellows": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the villainous crew they bullied": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the polished English noble": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "-- Water there is not a drop of water there !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "How was she to bear the change ?",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Without absolutely expressing a doubt whether the stalwart Puritan had acted as a man of conscience and integrity throughout the proceedings which have been sketched , they , nevertheless , hinted that he was about to build his house over an unquiet grave .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his house": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "a man of conscience and integrity": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an unquiet grave": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I ca n't bear to think that she 's dead . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "You would certainly have been burned , had you lived a few centuries ago .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He wore his pantaloons very loose and baggy in summer .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ You can have your dinner as soon as it 's done , ” replied the mother .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He held a white cloth -- it was a serviette he had brought with him -- over the lower part of his face , so that his mouth and jaws were completely hidden , and that was the reason of his muffled voice .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The Vances lived in number seven .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The Vances": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I did it for political reasons .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The ' G ' with the small ' t ' stands for ' Gesellschaft , ' which is the German for ' Company . '",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "' Edith is asleep , Aunt Shaw .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Aunt Shaw": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Her hand and wrist were so finely formed that she could wear sleeves not less bare of style than those in which the Blessed Virgin appeared to Italian painters ; and her profile as well as her stature and bearing seemed to gain the more dignity from her plain garments , which by the side of provincial fashion gave her the impressiveness of a fine quotation from the Bible , -- or from one of our elder poets , -- in a paragraph of to-day 's newspaper .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the side of provincial fashion": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "our elder poets": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "At first I thought he used to sleep in it , but afterwards I found that this was a mistake .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Buck Mulligan wiped again his razorblade .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Buck Mulligan": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He had sunken cheeks , a yellow complexion , a straight back , an ascetic aspect , and , with his arms dropped , the palms of hands outwards , resembled an idol .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "It was almost the tone of hope .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Three bedrooms in a row there , and three attics in a row above .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Three bedrooms in a row": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "three attics in a row above": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He poked his alpenstock , lance-fashion , into Winterbourne ’s bench and tried to crack the lump of sugar with his teeth .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The evening now was closed ; a serene stillness reigned ; and the chaste Queen of Night with her silver crescent faintly illuminated the hemisphere .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "she exclaimed , tore the flap of number one letter , paused and laid it aside .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Then there was Good , who is not like either of us , being short , dark , stout -- _ very _ stout -- with twinkling black eyes , in one of which an eyeglass is everlastingly fixed .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "But Mr Verloc knew his business , and remained undisturbed by any sort of æsthetic doubt about his appearance .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Mr Verloc": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his business": "ORG"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Rolling in cash . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Ca n't learn an old dog new tricks , as the saying is .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "In her younger days , Agnes had been a housekeeper for a young slaveholder , and in sustaining this relation had become the mother of two daughters .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the mother": "PER"
        },
        {
          "two daughters": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a housekeeper for a young slaveholder": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the mother of two daughters": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He must have been getting on for eighty in the year 1807 , earlier than which date I suppose I can hardly remember him , for I was born in 1802 .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Send Miss Sedley instantly to me , \" said Miss Pinkerton .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Miss Pinkerton": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Miss Sedley": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Then she stopped short and stooped down to wipe his wet face .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The Blaines were attached to no city .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The Blaines": "PER"
        },
        {
          "no city": "GPE"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She tells me that she has , for many years past , been in continual expectation of making a journey to England , which prevented her writing for information concerning this melancholy subject , by giving her hopes of making personal inquiries ; but family occurrences have still detained her in France , which country she now sees no prospect of quitting .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "which country she now sees no prospect of quitting": "GPE"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Emma was a tall , big-boned woman , with fair hair and large features .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a tall , big-boned woman": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "One ship is very much like another , and the sea is always the same .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the sea": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "One ship": "VEH"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "yet she had a good opinion of her own merit , -- truly , she said long prayers , -- and sometimes read her Week 's Preparation : she dreaded that horrid place vulgarly called _ hell _ , the regions below ; but whether her 's was a mounting spirit , I can not pretend to determine ; or what sort of a planet would have been proper for her , when she left her _ material _ part in this world , let metaphysicians settle ; I have nothing to say to her unclothed spirit .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "this world": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the regions below": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Caroline , or Sister Carrie , as she had been half affectionately termed by the family , was possessed of a mind rudimentary in its power of observation and analysis .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Sister Carrie": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the family": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Having premised thus much , we will now detain those who like our bill of fare no longer from their diet , and shall proceed directly to serve up the first course of our history for their entertainment .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "those who like our bill of fare": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Your mamma is quite well and happy . \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Your mamma": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Miss Cowley left the delights ( and drudgeries ) of her home life early in the war and came up to London , where she entered an officers ’ hospital .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Miss Cowley": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an officers ’ hospital": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "As for the blend of perfume , it was dreamily intoxicating .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I came upon the spot unexpectedly , finding it entirely deserted , with no signs of having been recently occupied as a camp .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the spot": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "a camp": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "If the hussy stood up for judgment before us five , that are now here in a knot together , would she come off with such a sentence as the worshipful magistrates have awarded ?",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the hussy": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the worshipful magistrates": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "At last I spoke .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Reckon you 're no good for anythin ' but eatin ' .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Overhead the stars shone gloriously .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "No lands neither ? \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The third party of the group , Gregory ’s sister Rosamond , who had her brother ’s braids of red hair , but a kindlier face underneath them , laughed with such mixture of admiration and disapproval as she gave commonly to the family oracle .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the group": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the family oracle": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Rosamond , who had her brother ’s braids of red hair , but a kindlier face underneath them": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" What do you imagine that it means ? \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "' Edith !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Maybe he can do something .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She blushed at herself , and seeing her reflection blush , blushed the more .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Now , I know that there are seventeen steps , because I have both seen and observed .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "seventeen steps": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Was it so irreconcilable , Warwick wondered , as still to peal out the curfew bell , which at nine o'clock at night had clamorously warned all negroes , slave or free , that it was unlawful for them to be abroad after that hour , under penalty of imprisonment or whipping ?",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "all negroes": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ It might be London . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Find any mineral ? \" asked Cameron , presently .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She could see that he was nervous ; one would expect a bony young man with his face slightly reddened by the wind , and his hair not altogether smooth , to be nervous in such a party .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a bony young man": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "It 's her being so long ! \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Once she crept into the dining-room and found it empty , though a partly finished meal was on the table and chairs and plates looked as if they had been hastily pushed back when the diners rose suddenly for some reason .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the diners": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the dining-room": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I began now seriously to reflect upon what I had done , and how justly I was overtaken by the judgment of Heaven for my wicked leaving my father ’s house , and abandoning my duty .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my father": "PER"
        },
        {
          "father ’s house": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "my father ’s house": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Spare the rod and spile the child , as the Good Book says .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the child": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Do n't say that , uncle , \" she pleaded .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I say that one might do a thousand things instead , and that whenever I really come there I have the sense of hairbreadth escape .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "But though the picture lies thus tranced , and though this pine-tree shakes down its sighs like leaves upon this shepherd 's head , yet all were vain , unless the shepherd 's eye were fixed upon the magic stream before him .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the shepherd": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the magic stream before him": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "And if turning up my hair makes me one , I 'll wear it in two tails till I 'm twenty , \" cried Jo , pulling off her net , and shaking down a chestnut mane .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "But your absurd words are as bad as Jo 's slang . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "All in all Beatrice O'Hara absorbed the sort of education that will be quite impossible ever again ; a tutelage measured by the number of things and people one could be contemptuous of and charming about ; a culture rich in all arts and traditions , barren of all ideas , in the last of those days when the great gardener clipped the inferior roses to produce one perfect bud .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Beatrice O'Hara": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the great gardener": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I took a seat at the end of the hearthstone opposite that towards which my landlord advanced , and filled up an interval of silence by attempting to caress the canine mother , who had left her nursery , and was sneaking wolfishly to the back of my legs , her lip curled up , and her white teeth watering for a snatch .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my landlord": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" We 're goin ' t ' move t ' morrah -- sure , \" he said pompously to a group in the company street .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the company street": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "a group in the company street": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Do you not want to know who has taken it ? ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" My poor child , \" said Miss Watkin , opening her arms .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Miss Watkin": "PER"
        },
        {
          "My poor child": "PER"
        },
        {
          "poor child": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "So much to see -- theatres , crowds , fine houses -- oh , you 'll like that . ”",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "fine houses": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He 'll play hookey this evening , * and [ * Southwestern for “ afternoon ” ] I 'll just be obleeged to make him work , tomorrow , to punish him .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Was it a girl or a boy ? \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a boy": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a girl": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The last of these voyages not proving very fortunate , I grew weary of the sea , and intended to stay at home with my wife and family .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my wife": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the sea": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The players closed around , flushed and muddy , and he went among them , glad to go in .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The players": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He gave us good food , good lodging , and kind words ; he spoke as kindly to us as he did to his little children .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his little children": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "By this curious turn of disposition I have gained the reputation of deliberate heartlessness ; how undeserved , I alone can appreciate .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Would the fall NEVER come to an end !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ You might transpose the words anywhere .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Sublime ideas filled her young mind -- always connected with devotional sentiments ; extemporary effusions of gratitude , and rhapsodies of praise would burst often from her , when she listened to the birds , or pursued the deer .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "So they were at last going to fight .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "She pretended that she was making a flower-bed , and she stuck big scarlet hibiscus blossoms into little heaps of earth , all the time growing more and more angry and muttering to herself the things she would say and the names she would call Saidie when she returned .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Even now , a bare half hour after breakfast , his jaws were moving with a rhythmical , champing motion .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I took my berth and went aboard , and that afternoon the Natal passengers from the _ Edinburgh Castle _ transhipped , and we weighed and put to sea .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the _ Edinburgh Castle _": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Hopeless to try for a local artist ... .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a local artist": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "As I looked at my friend standing there by the companion-ladder , I thought that if he only let his grow a little , put one of those chain shirts on to his great shoulders , and took hold of a battle-axe and a horn mug , he might have sat as a model for that picture .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my friend standing there by the companion-ladder": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a model for that picture": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Drink and the devil had done for the rest -- Yo-ho-ho , and a bottle of rum ! \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "What 's the lodestar ? ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I know so little that I did n't even know their son 's name .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "their son": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He must fight his fight alone .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Though I was angry with old Cotter for alluding to me as a child , I puzzled my head to extract meaning from his unfinished sentences .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "old Cotter": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a child": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I have n't seen Jervis 's wonderful Scotch doctor yet , but I assure you that he will have to be VERY wonderful to make up for the rest of these people , especially the kindergarten teacher .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the kindergarten teacher": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Her son-in-law ’s heavy good nature inspired her with a sense of absolute safety .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Her son-in-law": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "yo , o , o !",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I returned to my book -- Bewick 's History of British Birds : the letterpress thereof I cared little for , generally speaking ; and yet there were certain introductory pages that , child as I was , I could not pass quite as a blank .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" It is too much for your strength , my child .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my child": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Good is so overpoweringly frivolous .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Lydia , my love , though you _ are _ the youngest , I dare say Mr. Bingley will dance with you at the next ball . ”",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Mr. Bingley": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" People say , \" said another , \" that the Reverend Master Dimmesdale , her godly pastor , takes it very grievously to heart that such a scandal should have come upon his congregation . \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "her godly pastor": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his congregation": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Obviously he and his father did not do .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his father": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The doctor shook his head .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The doctor": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The people round about are persuaded that I am , to put it as kindly as possible , exceedingly eccentric , for the news has travelled that I spend the day out of doors with a book , and that no mortal eye has ever yet seen me sew or cook .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The people round about": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He had put them as things of the bygone with his thought-images of heavy crowns and high castles .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "high castles": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Seventh month : Pleasing appearance and nice manners so striking that am promoted to waiting on the Sisters !",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the Sisters": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ I grant you that , ” he answered .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He was a constant attendant upon religious worship , and was noted for his general benevolence .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a constant attendant upon religious worship": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "It is true that I had a country walk on Thursday and came home in a dreadful mess , but as I have changed my clothes I ca n't imagine how you deduce it .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "As to Mary Jane , she is incorrigible , and my wife has given her notice , but there , again , I fail to see how you work it out . \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my wife": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Now go into the store with her , Emil , and get warm . ”",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the store": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "said the nurse , picking up the cork of the green bottle , which had fallen out on the pillow , as she stooped to take up the child .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the child": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the nurse": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Dorothea knew many passages of Pascal 's Pensees and of Jeremy Taylor by heart ; and to her the destinies of mankind , seen by the light of Christianity , made the solicitudes of feminine fashion appear an occupation for Bedlam .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Jeremy Taylor": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "( _ Mem .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Imagine to yourself a small , withered , yellow-faced man of sixty-three , with thin hands , large brown eyes , a head of grizzled hair cut short and standing up like a half-worn scrubbing-brush -- total weight in my clothes , nine stone six -- and you will get a very fair idea of Allan Quatermain , commonly called Hunter Quatermain , or by the natives ‘ Macumazahn ’ -- Anglicè , he who keeps a bright look-out at night , or , in vulgar English , a sharp fellow who is not to be taken in .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Hunter Quatermain": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a small , withered , yellow-faced man of sixty-three , with thin hands , large brown eyes , a head of grizzled hair cut short and standing up like a half-worn scrubbing-brush": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the natives": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a sharp fellow who is not to be taken in": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" No , I wo n't send it anywhere . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "he asked .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I did not know what to do , for , as an English Churchman , I have been taught to regard such things as in some measure idolatrous , and yet it seemed so ungracious to refuse an old lady meaning so well and in such a state of mind .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "an English Churchman": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an old lady meaning so well and in such a state of mind": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Indeed , not only would he be reckless and sadly given to making blots in the afternoon , but some days he went further , and was rather noisy .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "You know my methods .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Will you give me a lump of sugar ? ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "It might be , too , that a witch , like old Mistress Hibbins , the bitter-tempered widow of the magistrate , was to die upon the gallows .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the bitter-tempered widow of the magistrate": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a witch": "PER"
        },
        {
          "old Mistress Hibbins": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Although nearly forty years of age at the time of which we write , Agnes was still exceedingly handsome .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Good-morning , \" answered Warwick .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Why ? \" he challenged , sturdily .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "But Beatrice was critical about American women , especially the floating population of ex-Westerners .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "American women": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the floating population of ex-Westerners": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "And yet I believe that my eyes are as good as yours . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "It might be that an Antinomian , a Quaker , or other heterodox religionist , was to be scourged out of the town , or an idle or vagrant Indian , whom the white man 's firewater had made riotous about the streets , was to be driven with stripes into the shadow of the forest .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the street": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "the streets": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "the white man": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an Antinomian": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a Quaker": "PER"
        },
        {
          "other heterodox religionist": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an idle or vagrant Indian , whom the white man 's firewater had made riotous about the streets": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the forest": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Oh , no ! \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Naturally I did myself .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "he said , stepping forward and handing twopence to the gatekeeper ; \" let the young woman pass . \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the gatekeeper": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the young woman": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He was probably trying to become acquainted with them before they got into the swim .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Oh yes ; do n’t grin : I liked her extremely and am glad to this day to think she liked me , too .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "I will if you will . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "A two minutes ' walk brought Warwick -- the name he had registered under , and as we shall call him -- to the market-house , the central feature of Patesville , from both the commercial and the picturesque points of view .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the market-house": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Whether I have remained so I known not , you must judge of that .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "said the girl , in a soft , though not particularly low voice .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the girl": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ God have mercy on his soul , ” said my aunt piously .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "my aunt": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his soul": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" MISS JEMIMA ! \"",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "MISS JEMIMA": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "If ever he mentioned it , the captain blew through his nose so loudly that you might say he roared , and stared my poor father out of the room .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the captain": "PER"
        },
        {
          "my poor father": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the room": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" I did n't know , sir , \" she began , \" that -- \" and she stopped embarrassed .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "THE MAGNET ATTRACTING -- A WAIF AMID FORCES When Caroline Meeber boarded the afternoon train for Chicago , her total outfit consisted of a small trunk , a cheap imitation alligator-skin satchel , a small lunch in a paper box , and a yellow leather snap purse , containing her ticket , a scrap of paper with her sister 's address in Van Buren Street , and four dollars in money .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Caroline Meeber": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Van Buren Street": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "her sister": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "CHAPTER 1 .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The field he was in this morning sloped to a ridge called Norcombe Hill .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Norcombe Hill": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "The field he was in this morning": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "a ridge": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "How are the secondhand breeks ?",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "You know as much as I do now .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Those poor little tots are going to enjoy the perfectly new sensation of being able to breathe at night .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Those poor little tots": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "In answer to a quick command , the girl went forward to take her place in the boat .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the girl": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the boat": "VEH"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ But after all , what of it ?",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Was n’t the old cat in a rage when she found out ?",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the old cat": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "We waited in fact till two nights later ; but that same evening , before we scattered , he brought out what was in his mind .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Perhaps a fifth part of her mind was thus occupied , and the remaining parts leapt over the little barrier of day which interposed between Monday morning and this rather subdued moment , and played with the things one does voluntarily and normally in the daylight .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" True , farmer . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "said the mother .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I went out to France again , as you know .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The water shone pacifically ; the sky , without a speck , was a benign immensity of unstained light ; the very mist on the Essex marsh was like a gauzy and radiant fabric , hung from the wooded rises inland , and draping the low shores in diaphanous folds .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the Essex marsh": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the low shores": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Then the customer of comparatively tender years would get suddenly disconcerted at having to deal with a woman , and with rage in his heart would proffer a request for a bottle of marking ink , retail value sixpence ( price in Verloc ’s shop one-and-sixpence ) , which , once outside , he would drop stealthily into the gutter .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the customer": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a woman": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Verloc ’s shop": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "My garden is surrounded by cornfields and meadows , and beyond are great stretches of sandy heath and pine forests , and where the forests leave off the bare heath begins again ; but the forests are beautiful in their lofty , pink-stemmed vastness , far overhead the crowns of softest gray-green , and underfoot a bright green wortleberry carpet , and everywhere the breathless silence ; and the bare heaths are beautiful too , for one can see across them into eternity almost , and to go out on to them with one ’s face towards the setting sun is like going into the very presence of God .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "My garden": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "sandy heath": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "pine forests": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the forests": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the bare heath": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the bare heaths": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Her daughter ’s future was obviously assured , and even as to her son Stevie she need have no anxiety .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Her daughter": "PER"
        },
        {
          "her son": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The poet delights in disorder only .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The poet": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "She was a nice mother but she was not so nice when she cried .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a nice mothe": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I bought eleven hot-water bottles this afternoon ( every one that the village drug store contained ) likewise some woolen blankets and padded quilts .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the village drug store": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The visitor sat and listened to her retreating feet .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The visitor": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Although the fire was burning up briskly , she was surprised to see that her visitor still wore his hat and coat , standing with his back to her and staring out of the window at the falling snow in the yard .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "her visitor": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the yard": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Then , as the fire dropped behind the domed peak , a change , a cold and darkening blight , passed down the black spear-pointed slopes over all that mountain world .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "all that mountain world": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the black spear-pointed slopes": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Whether sea-going people were short of money about that time , or were short of faith and preferred cork jackets , I do n’t know ; all I know is , that there was but one solitary bidding , and that was from an attorney connected with the bill-broking business , who offered two pounds in cash , and the balance in sherry , but declined to be guaranteed from drowning on any higher bargain .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "sea-going people": "PER"
        },
        {
          "an attorney connected with the bill-broking business": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "My father ’s eyes had closed upon the light of this world six months , when mine opened on it .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "My father": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Peter Kronborg was sitting in his wife 's room , holding the bundle which contained his son .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Peter Kronborg": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his son": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his wife": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He quitted the fire and dropped back into his chair .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" I do n't think it 's fair for some girls to have plenty of pretty things , and other girls nothing at all , \" added little Amy , with an injured sniff .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "some girls": "PER"
        },
        {
          "other girls": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He had a black , drooping mustache , and a chin like a rock .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "For the thousandth time he felt himself baffled by this calm , goggle-eyed boy who treated him with such supercilious coolness .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "this calm , goggle-eyed boy who treated him with such supercilious coolness": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Never mind .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "That ’s the only way I ever understand . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He chuckled to himself and rubbed his long , nervous hands together .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Stephen had answered : Stephen Dedalus .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Stephen Dedalus": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The man below growled under his breath , and again the spurs jingled .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The man": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Men were better , or more timid .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He kills his mother but he ca n’t wear grey trousers .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "his mother": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "He was swelled with a tale he had heard from a reliable friend , who had heard it from a truthful cavalryman , who had heard it from his trustworthy brother , one of the orderlies at division headquarters .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "division headquarters": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "a reliable friend": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a truthful cavalryman": "PER"
        },
        {
          "his trustworthy brother , one of the orderlies at division headquarters": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "It is true .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ I got these from that stall where y' ave ter get them marbles in them holes .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" When I hear you give your reasons , \" I remarked , \" the thing always appears to me to be so ridiculously simple that I could easily do it myself , though at each successive instance of your reasoning I am baffled until you explain your process .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "In a commercial transaction of the retail order much depends on the seller ’s engaging and amiable aspect .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the seller": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ Thanks for thy pains , ” I said , blowing blue rings into the air .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The ship was no sooner out of the Humber than the wind began to blow and the sea to rise in a most frightful manner ; and , as I had never been at sea before , I was most inexpressibly sick in body and terrified in mind .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The ship": "VEH"
        },
        {
          "the Humber": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the sea": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "They did not see him again for several days , nor did the captain accord them more than the surliest of grunts when he was forced to speak to them .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the captain": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "I do not know why I should fear death , I who have died twice and am still alive ; but yet I have the same horror of it as you who have never died , and it is because of this terror of death , I believe , that I am so convinced of my mortality .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "These belong to the farm , which is the only house near us .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the farm": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "the only house near us": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "In a panic of despair and terror Anthony was brought back to America , wedded to a vague melancholy that was to stay beside him through the rest of his life .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The murderer , he recalled , had been tried and sentenced to imprisonment for life , but was pardoned by a merciful governor after serving a year of his sentence .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "The murderer": "PER"
        },
        {
          "a merciful governor": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "The oldest of the colts raised his head , pricked his ears , and said , “ There are the hounds ! ” and immediately cantered off , followed by the rest of us to the upper part of the field , where we could look over the hedge and see several fields beyond .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the field": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "the colts": "PER"
        },
        {
          "several fields beyond": "LOC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "His coats were execrable ; his hat not to be handled .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Possibly , some people might suspect him of a degree of under-bred pride ; I have a sympathetic chord within that tells me it is nothing of the sort : I know , by instinct , his reserve springs from an aversion to showy displays of feeling -- to manifestations of mutual kindliness .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "some people": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "Alexandra went into the store to have her purchases packed in the egg-boxes , and to get warm before she set out on her long cold drive .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the store": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Bless my soul alive ! \" she said , going off at a tangent ; \" ai n't you done them taters _ yet _ , Millie ? \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "An ’ I ’ve always had ways of hearin ’ about him . ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "As the entire working staff of the institution was present , I thought it a good opportunity to emphasize the fact that all of these upsetting , innovations come straight from headquarters , and not out of my excitable brain .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the institution": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "See ? ”",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ And so this is your first visit to Chicago , ” he observed .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "The long contagion of the “ Derby ” hat arrived : one season the crown of this hat would be a bucket ; the next it would be a spoon .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "And here he comes , if I am not mistaken , to resolve all our doubts . \"",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "“ You always were a shocking liar , ” said Tuppence severely , “ though you did once persuade Sister Greenbank that the doctor had ordered you beer as a tonic , but forgotten to write it on the chart .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "a shocking liar": "PER"
        },
        {
          "Sister Greenbank": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the doctor": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "\" Oh , do n't take him away yet , \" she moaned .",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "Wild-eyed , choking clerks stampeded through the passages full of smoke , silk hats and elderly business men could be seen rolling independently down the stairs .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "Wild-eyed , choking clerks": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the passages": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "elderly business men": "PER"
        },
        {
          "the stairs": "FAC"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    "",
    {
      "entities": []
    }
  ],
  [
    "He had now finished his breakfast ; but he was drinking a small cup of coffee , which had been served to him on a little table in the garden by one of the waiters who looked like an attache .",
    {
      "entities": [
        {
          "the garden": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "an attache": "PER"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
